import HOM1 from "./HOM1.mp4"
import HOM2 from "./HOM2.mp4"
import HOM3 from "./HOM3.mp4"
import HOM4 from "./HOM4.mp4"
import HOM5 from "./HOM5.mp4"
import HOM6 from "./HOM6.mp4"
import HOM7 from "./HOM7.mp4"
import HOM8 from "./HOM8.mp4"
import HOM9 from "./HOM9.mp4"
import HOM10 from "./HOM10.mp4"
import HOM11 from "./HOM11.mp4"
import HOM12 from "./HOM12.mp4"
import HOM13 from "./HOM13.mp4"
import HOM14 from "./HOM14.mp4"
import HOM15 from "./HOM15.mp4"
import HOM16 from "./HOM16.mp4"
import HOM17 from "./HOM17.mp4"
import HOM18 from "./HOM18.mp4"
import HOM19 from "./HOM19.mp4"
import HOM20 from "./HOM20.mp4"
import HOM21 from "./HOM21.mp4"
import HOM22 from "./HOM22.mp4"
import HOM23 from "./HOM23.mp4"
import HOM24 from "./HOM24.mp4"
import HOM25 from "./HOM25.mp4"
import HOM26 from "./HOM26.mp4"
import HOM27 from "./HOM27.mp4"
import HOM28 from "./HOM28.mp4"
import HOM29 from "./HOM29.mp4"
import HOM30 from "./HOM30.mp4"
import HOM31 from "./HOM31.mp4"
import HOM32 from "./HOM32.mp4"
import HOM33 from "./HOM33.mp4"
import HOM34 from "./HOM34.mp4"
import HOM35 from "./HOM35.mp4"
import HOM36 from "./HOM36.mp4"
import HOM37 from "./HOM37.mp4"
import HOM38 from "./HOM38.mp4"
import HOM39 from "./HOM39.mp4"
import HOM40 from "./HOM40.mp4"
import HOM41 from "./HOM41.mp4"
import HOM42 from "./HOM42.mp4"
import HOM43 from "./HOM43.mp4"
import HOM44 from "./HOM44.mp4"
import HOM45 from "./HOM45.mp4"
import HOM46 from "./HOM46.mp4"
import HOM47 from "./HOM47.mp4"
import HOM48 from "./HOM48.mp4"
import HOM49 from "./HOM49.mp4"
import HOM50 from "./HOM50.mp4"
import HOM51 from "./HOM51.mp4"
import HOM52 from "./HOM52.mp4"
import HOM53 from "./HOM53.mp4"
import HOM54 from "./HOM54.mp4"
import HOM55 from "./HOM55.mp4"
import HOM56 from "./HOM56.mp4"
import HOM57 from "./HOM57.mp4"
import HOM58 from "./HOM58.mp4"
import HOM59 from "./HOM59.mp4"
import HOM60 from "./HOM60.mp4"
import HOM61 from "./HOM61.mp4"
import HOM62 from "./HOM62.mp4"
import HOM63 from "./HOM63.mp4"
import HOM64 from "./HOM64.mp4"
import HOM65 from "./HOM65.mp4"
import HOM66 from "./HOM66.mp4"
import HOM67 from "./HOM67.mp4"
import HOM68 from "./HOM68.mp4"
import HOM69 from "./HOM69.mp4"
import HOM70 from "./HOM70.mp4"
import HOM71 from "./HOM71.mp4"
import HOM72 from "./HOM72.mp4"
import HOM73 from "./HOM73.mp4"
import HOM74 from "./HOM74.mp4"
import HOM75 from "./HOM75.mp4"
import HOM76 from "./HOM76.mp4"
import HOM77 from "./HOM77.mp4"
import HOM78 from "./HOM78.mp4"
import HOM79 from "./HOM79.mp4"
import HOM80 from "./HOM80.mp4"
import HOM81 from "./HOM81.mp4"
import HOM82 from "./HOM82.mp4"
import HOM83 from "./HOM83.mp4"
import HOM84 from "./HOM84.mp4"
import HOM85 from "./HOM85.mp4"
import HOM86 from "./HOM86.mp4"
import HOM87 from "./HOM87.mp4"
import HOM88 from "./HOM88.mp4"
import HOM89 from "./HOM89.mp4"
import HOM90 from "./HOM90.mp4"
import HOM91 from "./HOM91.mp4"
import HOM92 from "./HOM92.mp4"
import HOM93 from "./HOM93.mp4"
import HOM94 from "./HOM94.mp4"
import HOM95 from "./HOM95.mp4"
import HOM96 from "./HOM96.mp4"
import HOM97 from "./HOM97.mp4"
import HOM98 from "./HOM98.mp4"
import HOM99 from "./HOM99.mp4"
import HOM100 from "./HOM100.mp4"
import HOM101 from "./HOM101.mp4"
import HOM102 from "./HOM102.mp4"
import HOM103 from "./HOM103.mp4"
import HOM104 from "./HOM104.mp4"
import HOM105 from "./HOM105.mp4"
import HOM106 from "./HOM106.mp4"
import HOM107 from "./HOM107.mp4"
import HOM108 from "./HOM108.mp4"
import HOM109 from "./HOM109.mp4"
import HOM110 from "./HOM110.mp4"
import HOM111 from "./HOM111.mp4"



export const homAlo  = [
    {
        id: 695,
        videoFile: HOM111,
        rusQuestion: "ткань",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "cloth or material for making clothes, covering furniture, etc.:",
        answer: "fabric",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 694,
        videoFile: HOM110,
        rusQuestion: "пускать слюни",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to allow saliva (= liquid in the mouth) to flow out of your mouth: ",
        answer: "drool",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 693,
        videoFile: HOM109,
        rusQuestion: "начинать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to start to talk about a particular subject: raise a matter for discussion or consideration.",
        answer: "bring up",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 692,
        videoFile: HOM108,
        rusQuestion: "малыш",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a young child: ",
        answer: "tyke",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 691,
        videoFile: HOM107,
        rusQuestion: "обезумевший",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "extremely worried, nervous, or upset: ",
        answer: "distraught",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 690,
        videoFile: HOM106,
        rusQuestion: "пощечина",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a quick hit with the flat part of the hand or other flat object: ",
        answer: "slap",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 689,
        videoFile: HOM105,
        rusQuestion: "перехитрить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to outwit ",
        answer: "outsmart",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 688,
        videoFile: HOM104,
        rusQuestion: "койоны",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "another word for testicle s: ",
        answer: "cojones",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 687,
        videoFile: HOM103,
        rusQuestion: "вязаный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "made using wool or thick cotton and two long needles: ",
        answer: "knitted",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 686,
        videoFile: HOM102,
        rusQuestion: "белье для стирки",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the dirty clothes and sheets that need to be, are being, or have been washed: ",
        answer: "laundry",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 685,
        videoFile: HOM101,
        rusQuestion: "нрав",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the tendency to become angry very quickly: ",
        answer: "temper",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 684,
        videoFile: HOM100,
        rusQuestion: "портить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to destroy or reduce the pleasure, interest, or beauty of something: ",
        answer: "spoil",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 683,
        videoFile: HOM99,
        rusQuestion: "бессвязный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "too long and confused:",
        answer: "rambling",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 682,
        videoFile: HOM98,
        rusQuestion: "автостоп",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to travel by getting free rides in someone else's vehicle: ",
        answer: "hitchhike",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 681,
        videoFile: HOM97,
        rusQuestion: "взлетная полоса",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a long, level piece of ground with a specially prepared smooth, hard surface on which aircraft take off and land",
        answer: "runway",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 680,
        videoFile: HOM96,
        rusQuestion: "вечный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "continuing for ever in the same way: ",
        answer: "perpetual",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 679,
        videoFile: HOM95,
        rusQuestion: "потрясен",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "kill someone using a firearm.",
        answer: "blow away",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 678,
        videoFile: HOM94,
        rusQuestion: "закружить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to (cause something to) turn around in circles: ",
        answer: "whirl",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 677,
        videoFile: HOM93,
        rusQuestion: "сани",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of sledge pulled by animals, especially horses or dogs",
        answer: "sleigh",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 676,
        videoFile: HOM92,
        rusQuestion: "блестеть",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to shine by reflecting light from a wet or smooth surface: ",
        answer: "glisten",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 675,
        videoFile: HOM91,
        rusQuestion: "глина",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "thick, heavy soil that is soft when wet, and hard when dry or baked, used for making bricks and containers",
        answer: "clay",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 674,
        videoFile: HOM90,
        rusQuestion: "болтающийся",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "hanging loosely: ",
        answer: "dangly",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 673,
        videoFile: HOM89,
        rusQuestion: "форель",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a fish that lives in rivers and lakes, or lives in the sea but returns to rivers to produce its eggs, that is a popular food: ",
        answer: "trout",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 672,
        videoFile: HOM88,
        rusQuestion: "сгнивший",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to decay, or to cause something to decay or weaken: ",
        answer: "rot",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 671,
        videoFile: HOM87,
        rusQuestion: "остролист",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small evergreen tree (= one that never loses its leaves) with shiny, sharp leaves and small, round, red fruit. Holly is often used as a Christmas decoration in Europe and North America.",
        answer: "holly",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 670,
        videoFile: HOM86,
        rusQuestion: "ветвь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large branch of a tree",
        answer: "bough",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 669,
        videoFile: HOM85,
        rusQuestion: "зал , коридор",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the area just inside the main entrance of a house, apartment, or other building that leads to other rooms and usually to the stairs:",
        answer: "hall",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 668,
        videoFile: HOM84,
        rusQuestion: "настил",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a wooden floor built outside, where people can sit and relax",
        answer: "deck",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 667,
        videoFile: HOM83,
        rusQuestion: "веселый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "happy and smiling: ",
        answer: "jolly",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 666,
        videoFile: HOM82,
        rusQuestion: "омела",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an evergreen plant (= one that never loses its leaves) that grows on trees, with small, white fruits and pale yellow flowers. Mistletoe is often used as a Christmas decoration, and it is traditional to kiss someone under it: ",
        answer: "mistletoe",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 665,
        videoFile: HOM81,
        rusQuestion: "магазинный вор",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who takes goods illegally from a shop without paying for them: ",
        answer: "shoplifter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 664,
        videoFile: HOM80,
        rusQuestion: "кроме этого",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "except: ",
        answer: "other than that",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 663,
        videoFile: HOM79,
        rusQuestion: "полоскание",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to use water to clean the soap or dirt from something: ",
        answer: "rinse",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 662,
        videoFile: HOM78,
        rusQuestion: "пупок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "navel.. the small round part in the middle of the stomach that is left after the umbilical cord (= the long tube of flesh joining the baby to its mother) has been cut at birth",
        answer: "belly button",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 661,
        videoFile: HOM77,
        rusQuestion: "расщелина",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small, narrow crack or space, especially in the surface of rock",
        answer: "crevice",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 660,
        videoFile: HOM76,
        rusQuestion: "запасной",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "something that is always ready for use, especially if a regular one fails: ",
        answer: "standby",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 659,
        videoFile: HOM75,
        rusQuestion: "автоответчик",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a device connected to a phone that answers calls automatically and records messages from the person calling: ",
        answer: "answering machine",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 658,
        videoFile: HOM74,
        rusQuestion: "застревать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to (cause to) become stuck in a place or position: ",
        answer: "lodge",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 657,
        videoFile: HOM73,
        rusQuestion: "проглотить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to eat or drink something: ",
        answer: "ingest",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 656,
        videoFile: HOM72,
        rusQuestion: "семья , хозяйство",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a group of people, often a family, who live together: ",
        answer: "household",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 655,
        videoFile: HOM71,
        rusQuestion: "близкие",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "nearest in space or relationship:",
        answer: "immediate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 654,
        videoFile: HOM70,
        rusQuestion: "ссора",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a loud argument or disagreement: ",
        answer: "altercation",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 653,
        videoFile: HOM69,
        rusQuestion: "гипер",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "having too much of a quality:",
        answer: "hyper",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 652,
        videoFile: HOM68,
        rusQuestion: "вышел из строя",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If something someone says or does is out of order, it is unpleasant or not suitable and it is likely to upset or offend people: ",
        answer: "out of order",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 651,
        videoFile: HOM67,
        rusQuestion: "слабак",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who is not strong, brave, or confident: ",
        answer: "wimp",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 650,
        videoFile: HOM66,
        rusQuestion: "квашеная капуста",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "cabbage that has been cut into small pieces and preserved in salt",
        answer: "sauerkraut",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 649,
        videoFile: HOM65,
        rusQuestion: "заплесневелый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(of food, esp. old food, or objects that have been left too long in warm, wet places) covered or filled with a soft green, blue, gray, or black growth, usually undesirable but thought to add a desirable taste to some cheeses: ",
        answer: "moldy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 648,
        videoFile: HOM64,
        rusQuestion: "пятно",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a mark or spot that does not have a regular shape: ",
        answer: "splotch",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 647,
        videoFile: HOM63,
        rusQuestion: "пьяница",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who often drinks too much alcohol",
        answer: "sot",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 646,
        videoFile: HOM62,
        rusQuestion: "грешный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "against the rules of a religion or morally wrong: ",
        answer: "sinful",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 645,
        videoFile: HOM61,
        rusQuestion: "драгоценный камень",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a jewel (= precious stone), especially when cut into a particular regular shape",
        answer: "gem",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 644,
        videoFile: HOM60,
        rusQuestion: "дрянь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who is very unpleasant or does very unpleasant things",
        answer: "rotter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 643,
        videoFile: HOM59,
        rusQuestion: "лом",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a heavy iron bar with a bent end that is used to help lift heavy objects off the ground or to force things open:",
        answer: "crowbar",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 642,
        videoFile: HOM58,
        rusQuestion: "денежный запас",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "cash lying idle, not being used for payments.",
        answer: "cash hoard",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 641,
        videoFile: HOM57,
        rusQuestion: "рыночные ценные бумаги",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a share, bond, etc. that can easily be bought and sold: ",
        answer: "marketable security",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 640,
        videoFile: HOM56,
        rusQuestion: "ювелирные изделия , драгоценности",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "decorative objects worn on your clothes or body that are usually made from valuable metals, such as gold and silver, and precious stones: ",
        answer: "jewelry",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 639,
        videoFile: HOM55,
        rusQuestion: "первоклассный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "highest in standard or quality: ",
        answer: "top-flight",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 638,
        videoFile: HOM54,
        rusQuestion: "серебряный тунец",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "An object that is better than all of the other ones in it's category. ",
        answer: "silver tuna",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 637,
        videoFile: HOM53,
        rusQuestion: "свинец",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a chemical element that is a very heavy, soft, dark grey, poisonous metal, used especially in the past on roofs and for pipes and also for protection against radiation: ",
        answer: "lead",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 636,
        videoFile: HOM52,
        rusQuestion: "тесто , бабки",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "flour mixed with water and often yeast, fat, or sugar, so that it is ready for baking: ",
        answer: "dough",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 635,
        videoFile: HOM51,
        rusQuestion: "бить , колотить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to hit or beat repeatedly with a lot of force, or to crush something by hitting it repeatedly: ",
        answer: "pound",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 634,
        videoFile: HOM50,
        rusQuestion: "петарда , фейерверк",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a firework that makes a loud noise when it explodes",
        answer: "firecracker",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 633,
        videoFile: HOM49,
        rusQuestion: "тошнотворный , отвратительный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "extremely unpleasant and causing you to feel shock and anger: ",
        answer: "sickening",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 632,
        videoFile: HOM48,
        rusQuestion: "тарантул",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "any of various large spiders covered in hair, some of which have a poisonous bite",
        answer: "tarantula",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 631,
        videoFile: HOM47,
        rusQuestion: "универсал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a car with a lot of space behind the back seat and an extra door at the back for putting in large objects",
        answer: "station wagon",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 630,
        videoFile: HOM46,
        rusQuestion: "закрепить , застегивать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to (cause something to) become firmly fixed together, or in position, or closed: ",
        answer: "fasten",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 629,
        videoFile: HOM45,
        rusQuestion: "добраться до",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "Reach a certain point or goal",
        answer: "make it to",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 628,
        videoFile: HOM44,
        rusQuestion: "руководитель , вдохновитель",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who plans a difficult activity, often a crime, in detail and makes certain that it happens successfully:",
        answer: "mastermind",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 627,
        videoFile: HOM43,
        rusQuestion: "северный олень",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of deer that lives in the northern parts of Europe, Asia, and North America: ",
        answer: "reindeer",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 626,
        videoFile: HOM42,
        rusQuestion: "куропатка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a bird with a round body and a short tail that is sometimes hunted for food or for sport, or the meat of this bird",
        answer: "partridge",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 625,
        videoFile: HOM41,
        rusQuestion: "латать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to connect electronic or phone equipment to a system",
        answer: "patch",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 624,
        videoFile: HOM40,
        rusQuestion: "полноприводный автомобиль",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If a vehicle has four-wheel drive, its engine supplies power to all four wheels instead of the usual two, so that the vehicle can travel easily over difficult ground: ",
        answer: "four-wheel drive",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 623,
        videoFile: HOM39,
        rusQuestion: "поголовье",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the exact number of people in a place, or the act of counting them: ",
        answer: "head count",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 622,
        videoFile: HOM38,
        rusQuestion: "пробег , километраж",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the distance that a vehicle has travelled or the distance that it can travel using a particular amount of fuel: ",
        answer: "mileage",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 621,
        videoFile: HOM37,
        rusQuestion: "спать дольше обычного",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to sleep until later in the morning than you usually do: ",
        answer: "sleep in",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 620,
        videoFile: HOM36,
        rusQuestion: "ровно , острый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "exactly at the stated time: ",
        answer: "sharp",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 619,
        videoFile: HOM35,
        rusQuestion: "пописать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "informal for urinate ",
        answer: "pee",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 618,
        videoFile: HOM34,
        rusQuestion: "капризничать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If a person, especially a child, ooooo, they behave badly: ",
        answer: "act up",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 617,
        videoFile: HOM33,
        rusQuestion: "не в духе",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "in an unhappy mood: ",
        answer: "out of sorts",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 616,
        videoFile: HOM32,
        rusQuestion: "воссоединение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a social event for a group of people who have not seen each other for a long time: ",
        answer: "reunion",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 615,
        videoFile: HOM31,
        rusQuestion: "отбросы , нечисть",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a layer of unpleasant or unwanted material that has formed on the top of a liquid: ",
        answer: "scum",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 614,
        videoFile: HOM30,
        rusQuestion: "нарочно",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If you do something oooooo, you do it intentionally, not by accident: ",
        answer: "on purpose",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 613,
        videoFile: HOM29,
        rusQuestion: "блевать b",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to vomit:  b ",
        answer: "barf",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 612,
        videoFile: HOM28,
        rusQuestion: "обыкновенный , чистый , ровный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "not decorated in any way; with nothing added: ",
        answer: "plain",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 611,
        videoFile: HOM27,
        rusQuestion: "раз",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "multiplied by: ",
        answer: "times",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 610,
        videoFile: HOM26,
        rusQuestion: "чаевые",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to give someone who has provided you with a service an extra amount of money to thank them: ",
        answer: "tip",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 609,
        videoFile: HOM25,
        rusQuestion: "таможня",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the place at a port, airport, or border where travellers' bags are looked at to find out if any goods are being carried illegally:",
        answer: "customs",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 608,
        videoFile: HOM24,
        rusQuestion: "салфетка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small square piece of cloth or paper, used while you are eating to protect your clothes or to clean your mouth or fingers",
        answer: "napkin",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 607,
        videoFile: HOM23,
        rusQuestion: "яично-винный коктейль",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a drink made from milk, sugar, and eggs, often mixed with alcohol such as brandy or rum",
        answer: "eggnog",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 606,
        videoFile: HOM22,
        rusQuestion: "кража со взломом",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the crime of illegally entering a building and stealing things",
        answer: "burglary",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 605,
        videoFile: HOM21,
        rusQuestion: "мумия",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(especially in ancient Egypt) a dead body that is prevented from decaying by being treated with special substances before being wrapped in cloth",
        answer: "mummy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 604,
        videoFile: HOM20,
        rusQuestion: "мусорное ведро",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large container for rubbish from a house or other building, usually made of strong plastic or metal and kept outside",
        answer: "garbage can",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 603,
        videoFile: HOM19,
        rusQuestion: "тротуар",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a path with a hard surface on one or both sides of a road, that people walk on: ",
        answer: "sidewalk",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 602,
        videoFile: HOM18,
        rusQuestion: "квартал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the distance along a street from where one road crosses it to the place where the next road crosses it, or one part of a street like this, especially in a town or city: ",
        answer: "block",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 601,
        videoFile: HOM17,
        rusQuestion: "сгибать , гнуть",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to (cause to) curve:",
        answer: "bend",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 600,
        videoFile: HOM16,
        rusQuestion: "комок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a number of usually flat and/or small objects pressed tightly together:",
        answer: "wad",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 599,
        videoFile: HOM15,
        rusQuestion: "мокрота , слизь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a thick substance in your nose and throat that is produced when you have a cold",
        answer: "phlegm",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 598,
        videoFile: HOM14,
        rusQuestion: "раскладушка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: " a multifunctional furniture typically consisting of a sofa or couch that, underneath its seating cushions, hides a metal frame and thin mattress that can be unfolded or opened up to make a bed.",
        answer: "hide-a-bed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 597,
        videoFile: HOM13,
        rusQuestion: "дерьмо",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a rude word for solid waste, or an occasion when an animal or person produces solid waste: ",
        answer: "crap",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 596,
        videoFile: HOM12,
        rusQuestion: "блевать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to vomit: ",
        answer: "puke",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 595,
        videoFile: HOM11,
        rusQuestion: "ныть , скулить , хныкать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to make a long, high, sad sound:",
        answer: "whine",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 594,
        videoFile: HOM10,
        rusQuestion: "наркотик , дурак",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a silly person: ",
        answer: "dope",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 593,
        videoFile: HOM9,
        rusQuestion: "приют для сирот",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a home for children whose parents are dead or unable to care for them",
        answer: "orphanage",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 592,
        videoFile: HOM8,
        rusQuestion: "кишка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the long tube in the body of a person or animal, through which food moves during the process of digesting food: ",
        answer: "gut",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 591,
        videoFile: HOM7,
        rusQuestion: "орнамент , украшение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an object that is beautiful rather than useful: ",
        answer: "ornament",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 590,
        videoFile: HOM6,
        rusQuestion: "клей-пистолет",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a piece of equipment that heats glue and is used for crafts (= making pictures, models, etc.)",
        answer: "glue gun",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 589,
        videoFile: HOM5,
        rusQuestion: "козлиная бородка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small, usually pointed beard grown only on the chin, not the cheeks",
        answer: "goatee",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 588,
        videoFile: HOM4,
        rusQuestion: "адаптер напряжения",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the force of an electric current, measured in volts:",
        answer: "voltage adapter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 587,
        videoFile: HOM3,
        rusQuestion: "Придурок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a stupid person, usually a man:",
        answer: "jerk",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 586,
        videoFile: HOM2,
        rusQuestion: "рейтинг",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to judge the value or character of someone or something:",
        answer: "rate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 585,
        videoFile: HOM1,
        rusQuestion: "девицы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a young woman",
        answer: "wench",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
]